https://energizergrouplegal.com/Energizer-Privacy-Notice-USA.html

Text Only Versions
Select Languages
Arabic (Egypt)
English (Australia)
Chinese (Hong Kong)
Czech (Czechia)
Danish (Denmark)
Dutch (Belgium)
English (USA)
English (UK)
Estonian (Estonia)
Russian (Estonia)
Finnish (Finland)
English (S.Africa)
English(Singapore)
Arabic (Qatar)
English (Qatar)
French (France)
German (Germany)
German(Switzerland)
English(Ghana)
Greek (Greece)
Hebrew(Israel)
Hungarian (Hungary)
Ireland (ROI)
Indonesian (Indonesia)
Italian (Italy)
English(Kenya)
English(Canada)
Arabic (Lebanon)
English (Lebanon)
Arabic(Jordan)
English(Jordan)
Latvian (Latvia)
Lithuanian (Lithuania)
Malay (Malaysia)
English (Malaysia)
Norwegian (Norway)
Arabic (Oman)
English (Oman)
Polish (Poland)
Russian (Russia)
English (Republic Of Ireland)
Arabic (UAE)
English (UAE)
Serbia (RS)
Korean (South Korea)
Slovakian (Slovakia)
Spanish (Spain)
Sri Lanka (LK)
Swedish (Sweden)
English (Newzealand)
Portuguese (Portugal)
Thai (Thailand)
Ukraine (UA)
Vietnamese (Vietnam)
Website Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting our website. Energizer Holdings, Inc. and its affiliates (“Energizer”) own and operate this website. Energizer is a world leader in providing batteries and lighting products. In this privacy policy, we refer to all of the companies in our corporate group as "Energizer", "we", or "us".
This Website Privacy Policy explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your personal information is collected and used through this website.
Use of Websites
Our U.S. websites are intended for residents of the U.S. If you happen to live in another country, yet use our U.S. websites, any data collected about you with respect to your use of our websites will be transferred to the U.S. As such, please note that there may be different standards that apply to how your data may be used and protected than the standards in place in your country. Nevertheless, Energizer has put in place safeguards to ensure that your data is safeguarded and protected irrespective ofthe country. This includes obtaining written assurances from third parties assisting Energizer with its websites or given access to your data, which require them to adoptstandards that ensure an equivalent level of protection for your data as that adoptedby Energizer.
Information That We Collect from You
You may browse many sections of our websites without providing any personal information about yourself.
However, if you choose to purchase products through our websites,register for one of our promotions or services, ask us a question through our Contact Us link, apply for employment with us, or apply to become an approved supplier,we must collect certain information from you.
Ordering
If you place an order through one of our websites, we must obtain information from you relating to the order, including your name, billing and shipping addresses, order information, payment information, and your email address to confirm your order and shipping. This information is used for processing your order, confirming shipment and tocontact you in the event that we have trouble processing your order. Consistent with applicable laws and requirements, we retain order information to better serve you on future purchases, and may use your information to contact you in connection with other Energizer products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. Of course, you always have
the right to unsubscribe at any time from emails that you don’t want to receive from Energizer (and may do so via the unsubscribe link in the email, orby following one of the other unsubscribe methods described below in this Website Privacy Policy).
Registration
To register on our sites, you must complete the registration process by providing personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email, telephone number, as well as information relating to what you would like to receive from us. If you choose to register, you may also be asked to choose a user name and password. Please keep this information secure. If you choose to register, you have the right to unsubscribe at any time by contacting us through one of the contact options provided below (email, letter or telephone). Please give us 10 days to process your unsubscribe request.
Employment
If you apply for a job with Energizer through one of our websites, the information collected will include your name, contact details, the position(s) you are applying for, your qualifications for the position, your education and academic degrees, applicable licenses or certifications, prior employment history, references, and any other information that you choose to include about yourself. If you are accepted for an interview or employment, we will, of course, necessarily collect other relevant information from you and include it with that collected during the application process, and include it in your personnel file. The information that will be collected for purposes of your employment in the United States includes your Social Security number. That information and other employee personal information is protected in accordance with Energizer’s internal policies.
Supplier Portal
If you apply to become an approved supplier, the information we collect will includerelevant business information, such as the name, contact details, location and products or services offered by your organization, and information relating to pricing, sourcing, and other business practices. We may also request additional information fromyou, including an on-site audit or additional checking to ensure that our prospective partnership with you will be consistent with Energizer’s business, legal and compliance expectations for our partners. If you become an approved supplier, we will also require other relevant information from you that is relevant to our ongoing business relationship.
Newsletter and Email Communications
If you choose to sign-up for our newsletter or email communications online, you must submit certain basic information during the registration process. This information may include your name, email address, and a confirmation that you are over 18 years old. This information is used to send the newsletter or email communications electronically, and to ensure that we can provide you with appropriate customer service and respond to your inquiries.
Surveys
While visiting certain portions of our websites, you may be given the opportunity to provide feedback regarding various Energizer products. You may be given opportunitiesto rate Energizer products and to publicly ask and answer questions pertaining to Energizer products. In order to fully participate in these portions of the websites, youmay be asked to provide your full name and an email address, as well as a created online username which will be publicly linked to your product ratings, questions, answers and other comments. You will be required to agree to a set of terms and conditions which require, among other things, you to verify that you are over the age of 13. Youmay also be prompted to submit additional voluntary information, such as specific age range, gender, location, address, phone number, website, job title, and the length of time which you have used Energizer products. This information may be linked online to your chosen username. Energizer stores this additional information, if provided, and later uses it to help us better understand and respond to the collective feedback we receive.
Occasionally, we may invite you to participate in a survey or poll such as providing feedback on our websites’ site content, services, or products. Your responses will beanonymous unless you choose to provide your contact details so that we can provide you with additional information regarding the survey or poll.
For any information that we collect through our sites, Energizer or one of its partners becomes the owner of that data.
Cookies and Other Anonymous Web Tracking
Like most websites, we use "cookies" on our websites to help us serve you better on future visits, and to help us analyze web traffic for our sites, and evaluate and improve the content or functions of our sites. A cookie is a small text file which is sent by a website, accepted by a web browser and then placed on your hard drive. The information collected from cookies sent by Energizer and approved third parties assisting us with our websites lets us know that you visited our sites in the past, and helps you avoid having to re-enter information on each visit in order to use some of our products or services. Cookies also help us analyze use of our sites, and better aggregate useful information when site users provide feedback about our site or products. You can always set your browser to refuse all cookies from this and other websites that you may visit. This will provide you with more control over the acceptance of cookies on your hard drive. However, it is possible that some portions of this website will not function properly or may perform more slowly if you choose to reject cookies. By using our websites and not disabling cookies, you consent to allowing their use forthe described purposes. Remember also that disabling cookies is browser specific. For example, if you log on using Internet Explorer, you must also disable cookies in Safari if you use that browser at a different time. We may also collect information about your method of access such as your operating system (Windows 7, Windows 8, Mac, Linux, etc.) and your browser (Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Safari, etc.). We may use access method information along with information about site searches you run to serve you personalized content using third party vendors such as Sitefinity. Such personalized content applications do not collect and store personally identifiable information about you.
Except in the case of analytics cookies described herein, our websites do not track your use across multiple external websites, however, other websites to which we link may. Please review their privacy policies to understand how you may be tracked.
Social Platform Registrations and Social Media Plugins
Some of the Energizer websites permit you to use a third party social networking platform such as Facebook, Pinterest, Twitter and Google+. This includes use of social media plugins such as Facebook “Like,” Twitter “Tweet,” Pinterest “Pin,” Google “+1” buttons, etc. When you use these social networking platforms and plugins, your user name and password for the services and other information available about you or collected from you on these services may be shared with us. We may ask your permission repostyour Facebook or Twitter quotes on our websites. If you agree, you grant us the rightto use your posts on our websites for promotional purposes.
When you use social networking platforms and plugins, you share your information withthem and their privacy policy and applicable terms of use apply to the use and disclosure of such information. In addition, they may be able to collect information about you, including your activity on the Energizer websites, and they may notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of the Energizer websites. Such services may allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites for purposes of delivering more targeted advertising. Please note that their privacy policies and applicable terms of use may apply and we encourage you to read them. We may addnew social networking plugins and buttons to our websites from time to time.
Using and Sharing Information Collected
Energizer may share your information within the Energizer group of companies as well as with third parties that assist us with order fulfillment, job applicant screening,or with our websites, contests and sweepstakes, such as in providing the information for the purposes of improving our marketing or administration. This includes companies that provide analytics to us about use of our websites, so that we can evaluate useof our websites and continue to improve our website content.
Except as provided below in "Promotions and Third Parties," Energizer does not share or sell any personal information that you provide to us through our websites for any separate use by any third party. However, from time to time, we may provide aggregate(statistical) information about our customers, sales, online traffic patterns and related information to reputable third parties who help us improve our business and services, but these statistics do not include any personally identifying information.
In the event that we sell, assign or transfer all or part of the Energizer business, we may transfer your personal information to the buyer. However, the buyer, assignee,or transferee will be required to safeguard your personal information in a manner that is consistent with the requirements in this Privacy Policy
Promotions and Third Parties
From time to time, Energizer may run promotions offering special deals, coupons, discounts, chances to win contests, and other prizes. These promotions may involve third-parties. In order to participate in these promotions, Energizer may require certain basic information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, and date of birth. This and other required information may be stored by Energizer in order to help us better understand how we can design and market our products for you and others. This information may also be shared with any relevant third-party partners involved in the specific promotion for which you choose to sign-up. By signing up for the promotion, you consent to such sharing. In addition, certain third-parties may use your information to contact you in order to provide you with more information about their company and with further opportunities to make additional purchases.
International Visitors to Our Websites
Energizer is a global company.
As such, Energizer’s global data privacy framework includes practices for respecting and complying with the data privacy laws of other countries where we operate, including the laws and requirements that relate to transfer of personal information from those regions to the U.S.
The data transfer compliance provisions include implementation of the E.U. Standard Contractual Clauses and, until its invalidation in 2015, certification to the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor program for personal data transferred from the European Economic Area and Switzerland.
If you have questions about Energizer’s data protection practices, please email us at: privacy@energizer.com, or write to us at: Energizer Headquarters, 533 Maryville University Drive, St. Louis, MO 63141, ATTN: Legal Department, or call us at: (800) 383-7323.
Safeguarding Your Information
We follow applicable laws and requirements to protect your information. Among other things, Energizer has adopted physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards thatare designed to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, alteration, theft, unauthorized access, or unauthorized disclosure. We evaluate these safeguards on an ongoing basis to help minimize risks from new security threats as they become known. However, as is the case with all websites, we unfortunately are not able to guarantee 100% security for data collected through our public websites.
Our Commitment to Children's Privacy
Our websites are not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Energizer does not market any of its products online for children under the age of 13, nor does Energizer design its online applications, advertisements and other features to attract an audience of children under the age of 13. Although certain pages within the websitemay reference "kids," "children," or "students," Energizer strictly intends for such portions of the website to be used only by adults (such as parents and teachers) or children of the age 13 or older. Energizer adheres to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and does not knowingly register or otherwise collect personally identifiable information from any child under the age of 13 without the prior verifiable consent of the child's parent or guardian. However, we are allowed to collect personal information from a child for the one-time purpose of responding to an inquiry, answering an email, or seeking Verifiable Parental Consent at the request of the child under the age of 13.
Energizer does not sell or share information obtained from minors with any third parties for their own use. The third parties who may have access are those assisting us with or co-sponsoring our website fulfillments, such as for purposes of filling ordersor processing payments. We do not share a child's information with blogs or other sites where the information would be publically accessible.
If Energizer should inadvertently collect information from a child under the age of 13, we delete that information, except to the extent needed to seek Verifiable Parental Consent from the minor's parent or legal guardian. When Verifiable Parental Consentis obtained, we collect only that personal information from a minor that is relevant to the registration or purchase. We protect the information with security safeguards and confidentiality measures that are commensurate with the sensitivity of the information. Parents or legal guardians have the right to review their child's personal information, delete it, or withdraw permission to allow further collection or use of that information.
Update, Modify or Correct Your Information
Energizer takes reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is accurate and up-to-date for the purposes for which it was collected. We encourage you to contact us to update or correct your information if it changes or if you believe that any information that we have collected about you is inaccurate. Consistent with legal requirements and limitations, Energizer also permits you to obtain a copy of personal information that we hold about you. To do so, please email us at webmaster@energizer.com, or write to us at: Energizer headquarters, 533 Maryville University Drive, St. Louis, MO63141, ATTN: Legal Department.
Please note that we will likely require additional information from you in order to honor the request, such as to ensure proper authentication or to verify the Energizer company to which the information was provided.
Right to Unsubscribe
You have the right to unsubscribe from any services that we offer, if you no longer want to participate. To do so, please use our Contact Us link on this site for additional information, or email us at webmaster@energizer.com. Please note that if you already have requested products or services when you decide to withdraw consent, there may be a short period of time for us to update your preferences and ensure that we honor your request.
Links to Other Websites
Our websites may contain links to sites operated, controlled and maintained by independent third parties. We do not control the use of information you may provide to suchthird parties. If you access other websites using the links provided in our websites,the operators of the third-party sites may collect information from you which will then be used by them in accordance with their own privacy policies, not ours. Those policies may differ from ours. It is your responsibility to familiarize yourself with privacy policies on this website and other websites.
Changes to This Privacy Policy
As we continue to provide additional services and as the privacy laws and regulationsevolve, it may be necessary to revise or update this Policy. We encourage you to review this Policy from time to time, as you return to our site, so that you are familiarwith any changes. Please note that we use personal information in accordance with the privacy policy that was in effect at the time the information was collected.
Your California Privacy Rights
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information tothird parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to privacy@energizer.com, or write to us at: Energizer Headquarters, 533 Maryville University Drive, St. Louis, MO 63141, ATTN: Legal Department, or call us at: (800) 383-7323.
Contact Us / Additional Resources
For additional information or any concerns, please email us at: privacy@energizer.com, or write to us at: Energizer Legal Department, 533 Maryville University Dr., St. Louis, Missouri USA 63141 USA.
